[Episode 25]
It's the same taste
as it was 20 years ago.
Ling Yun Fei,
are you going to confess or not?
All my life,
I hate informers the most.
Execute!
Execute him!
Great!
Well done!
The traitor has been executed.
We may report to His Majesty.
Meng Ting Hui fulfilled her pledge on time.
She's eradicated the Huxiao Gang.
She lived up to my expectations.
The rest will be handled as you said.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Shen Zhi Shu.
Yes.
You have made great contributions
in arresting the Huxiao Gang
and investigating the Blood Moon Society,
so I specially promote you
to the fourth-rank Supervisory Censor.
You will
handle the entire Blood Moon Society case.
In addition, I'll transfer you to the border
to reinforce Qingzhou's defenses.
If you get solid evidence of treason,
you may act first and report later.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I will surely give my all to it
and live up to Your Majesty's expectations.
Rise.
Your Majesty,
I have found out
that the Blood Moon Society was created
by the remnants of Zhongwan.
Under the cover of Huiyin House,
they've been lurking
in the capital for many years,
winning over many high officials and nobles.
Its ambition to restore their nation
is obvious.
We are now doing our utmost
to arrest the remaining members.
Your Majesty,
I once followed the late emperor
to conquer Zhongwan.
Please allow me to lead elite troops
to eradicate the remnants of Zhongwan.
At my age,
if I could die in battle for our country,
I would feel proud of it.
Ruthless suppression
will only breed more hatred.
Moreover, Qingzhou borders Beijian.
In both internal and external crises,
the people will suffer.
Your Majesty is far-sighted.
According to my investigation,
Beijian once wanted
to jointly mine the Wanshan iron ore
at the border of Qingzhou.
If they collude with the Blood Moon Society,
it could cause great disaster.
Your Majesty,
I have an idea.
Without the use of force,
we can eliminate the external threat.
Your Majesty,
Beijian has proposed marriage,
willing to let their goddess marry you.
Their goddess is versed in astrology
and can also tell fortunes of the nation.
Her status is noble.
If Your Majesty marries her, the relationship
between the two countries will stay strong.
Though the Blood Moon Society
has wild ambitions,
it will be difficult for them
to stir up things with the help of Beijian.
Absurd!
How can a foreign woman
be the empress of our country?
Beijian is deploying troops on the border
while sending envoys for a marriage alliance.
Is this their sincerity or a threat?
Your Majesty,
if a marriage alliance can
bring ten years of peace to the border,
it might be a good idea.
We have built a trade alliance with Beijian.
Why do we need a marriage alliance
to seek peace?
Good relations between two countries
rely on strength.
Your Majesty is absolutely right.
Ministers will recommend the right person
to be the empress.
Now the position of the empress
has been vacant for a long time,
which has aroused Beijian's covetousness.
I beg Your Majesty
to appoint an empress as soon as possible
to end those barbarians' wishful thinking.
Beijian has already sent envoys
for a marriage alliance.
If not handled properly,
it may cause border conflicts.
You two, stop arguing.
I will carefully consider it myself.
Meng Ting Hui.
I have one more comment
for the memorial you just submitted.
Take a look
and see if there is anything unclear.
Beijian wants a marriage alliance,
but I don't want it.
What I want is only you.
Your Majesty,
I understand.
- Your Majesty.
- Enough.
All of you may leave.
Meng Ting Hui, you stay.
We take our leave.
- Just now--
- Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
I have an urgent matter to report.
What is it?
Your Majesty has been on the throne
for three years and has not yet married.
Your marriage is a major state affair,
the foundation of the nation.
Your Majesty,
if you do not wish for a marriage alliance,
I can
select a few talented, beautiful ladies
for Your Majesty.
You want me to run away from the palace?
No, I don't.
Just leave.
I'll take my leave.
Were you angry just now? Were you jealous?
Of course not.
Your Majesty is the ruler of a nation.
If I'm jealous of every woman,
I will overstep my bounds.
Indeed,
but I'm happy if you are.
Your Majesty.
What are you afraid of?
Where is the courage
you had in Wangxian Valley?
Your Majesty.
Please restrain yourself.
[Shen Mansion]
Zhi Li.
I am going to Qingzhou on business,
not being exiled to the far north.
People will laugh at me
for packing so many things.
Qingzhou is bitterly cold.
It's even frosty in June.
Zhi Shu, you care more about appearance
than warmth.
But you're away for official business,
so put aside your appearance for now.
Taking care of your health
is the most important thing.
You are so thoughtful,
as if you were my big sister.
Good idea.
From now on, I can be your big sister.
Please. Your little brother is only Nian.
I don't dare to compete with him.
Don't take it out again.
I'll go see if Father is done cooking.
I'll call you later.
Zhi Shu.
Listen to me.
The border is not as safe as the capital.
When you're alone outside,
you can't be too careful.
So I specially prepared this for you.
Be sure to wear it at all times.
Alright, put it in.
I know you too well.
You readily take it,
but then forget about it.
Today, I must personally put it on you.
Don't get handsy.
I'm already spoken for.
I must remain pure for Fu Zhi.
Sure, you're spoken for
and should remain pure.
I'll leave it here.
Nian.
Before I leave,
I want to entrust you with some things.
I don't know when I will return.
What worries me most is our family.
Father and Mother are getting old.
Zhi Li is still unmarried.
You must take good care of them,
especially Zhi Li.
Don't worry, Zhi Shu.
I will definitely protect her.
Just protection is not enough.
I've long known how you feel about Zhi Li.
I...
There's no need to hide it from me.
Zhi Li grew up with you.
I'm her own brother,
but she cares more about you than me.
I also know
that you are not simple.
You've had designs on Zhi Li from the start.
However,
I'm relieved
to entrust Zhi Li to you.
I did reveal my feelings to her,
but in her heart...
Don't worry.
Between her and Lord Gu,
there is nothing but the admiration
of a student for a teacher,
by no means true romantic feelings.
Even you know about this?
I wanted to talk to her personally,
but I always feel
that some topics are hard
to bring up between siblings.
During my absence,
you must keep an eye on her for me.
Don't let her be misled by Lord Gu.
We have had many arguments over Lord Gu.
She's currently avoiding me.
You're always carefree and unrestrained,
but when facing Zhi Li,
you're always cautious.
You just treasure her too much,
so you are overly cautious in action.
When it comes to love, you need some courage.
Otherwise, once you miss it,
you will regret it for life.
Moreover, you are in your prime
and have a bright future.
You're much better than Lord Gu.
No matter what,
you are over 20 years younger than him.
I only accept you
as my future brother-in-law.
I see.
I will never give up on Zhi Li.
- Father is cooking--
- Sweet and sour pork ribs.
- Let's go.
- Don't push me.
[Bofeng House]
His Majesty permitted Bofeng's reopening.
We have delicious dishes for you.
All drinks are half price.
- Welcome!
- Good!
Sir, please come in.
The Blood Moon Society acts secretly.
You must be extremely careful.
If there is anything unusual,
send word back immediately.
I'll act by imperial decree.
Don't worry, Your Majesty.
Director Meng,
you even personally made pastries for me.
It moves me so.
Who said they are for you?
I chatted with Director Meng last night
and mentioned layer cakes.
Last night?
Last night,
I talked to Your Majesty about my trip,
but I didn't see Director Meng there.
Mr. Shen.
Isn't Fu Zhi going to see you off?
Zhi, I brought some silver and banknotes.
- Zhi.
- And the withdrawal seals for money houses.
Zhi, you are too good to me.
We will have a long journey.
We can't treat ourselves poorly.
We?
Zhi, I am going on a business trip.
Guess what?
His Majesty has permitted Bofeng House
to reopen,
so merchants from various places
have sent invitations.
The head of the Qingzhou Chamber of Commerce
has sent invitations three times.
I have to go and inspect the place.
Zhi, I'm going to carry out a secret mission.
You can travel with Miss Yan
under the pretext of visiting relatives,
which can serve as a cover.
Great!
Zhi, let's get a bigger carriage.
We'll lay the fox fur blanket in it
and get your favorite pastries.
Zhi, you are so thoughtful.
Zhi, you are the best.
No, you are the best.
You are the best.
What are you two doing?
What are you doing?
I am returning now.
I can give you a ride.
Let's go.
I also need to return to the Censorate.
- Let's go.
- Wait.
The imperial palace and the Censorate
are located in opposite directions.
Zhi, let's go quickly. Take your sword.
Meng, take care of yourself while I'm away.
Remember to write to me.
Zhi, when I return,
I will officially propose marriage to you.
That day at the execution ground,
Gu Qin looked strange.
He must have a guilty conscience.
Tonight, I want to see
whether the Maojing pendant is here or not.
Mrs. Gu.
We're here to seek the truth.
I hope
you will haunt the real murderer.
Heaven and earth,
ancestors protect us.
- Don't panic when opening the coffin.
- Mrs. Gu, forgive us.
Heaven--
We're pressed for time.
Forgive us.
Someone is coming, Miss Meng.
Just one last step to go. Search.
Come on!
My lord, it...
Starting tomorrow,
send more monks to chant for my late wife
throughout the day.
Do not let any ghost disturb my late wife.
Yes.
[Library]
Your Majesty.
Lord Gu claims that the Maojing pendant
was buried with his late wife,
but Yin Qing and I opened the coffin
and couldn't find it.
Even more suspicious,
he took people to check overnight,
which shows he has a guilty conscience.
Gu Qin acted
as if he deeply loved his late wife.
Good acting.
But now, even if we expose his lies,
we have no solid evidence
that he provided cover for Ling Yun Fei.
Then we still cannot take him down.
I have considered
to confront him,
but he can argue that the Maojing pendant
was stolen by tomb robbers.
Then we can do nothing about it.
Under the guise of cleaning house,
on the surface,
I aim to supervise all officials.
But in fact,
I want to find clues related to Gu Qin.
What I want is not just to expose a lie,
but to make sure no one in the court
dares to deceive me again.
It's to kill two birds with one stone.
What happened to your hand?
Probably scratched myself
when opening the coffin.
It's not serious.
What did I give you the Light Cavalry for?
Yin Qing alone can help me
with small things like opening coffins.
No need to trouble the Light Cavalry.
Let me apply medicine for you.
Your Majesty.
What is it?
You're staying up late reading books again.
It harms your health.
I am truly worried about your body.
So I specially made tonic soup for you.
Your Majesty, what's wrong?
I've been staying up late reading these days.
I feel unwell,
so I indeed need the tonic soup.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, you stay up late reading,
which harms your health.
After finishing the tonic soup
that I specially prepared for you,
please go to bed.
You may leave now.
I'll take my leave.
Is he gone?
You're always bold.
Why were you afraid of him?
Whenever I hear Chief Steward You's voice,
I feel inexplicably nervous.
Didn't Your Majesty feel the same just now?
I rarely see you like this.
Stop laughing at me.
I just opened a coffin,
and now I have to hide behind bookshelves.
I have to act secretly,
whether on personal affairs or not.
Being with Your Majesty
is even more nerve-wracking
than handling corrupt officials.
You are afraid,
but I like it.
Director Meng.
I have great news.
Guess what?
You seem so excited.
It seems you got quite useful clues.
Tell me.
Li Xin, the Vice Minister of Revenue,
embezzled money
and gave all his ill-gotten wealth
to his wife to manage.
But his wife keeps several young lovers
behind his back.
I can give my only ill-gotten house
to the Censorate right now.
You can see there is nothing expensive here.
I never hide illicit money here.
Mr. Yin, I...
- Honey.
- You witch!
- How dare you spend my money
on your darn lovers!
Mr. Li, it's not my fault.
You're a kept man!
It's more than that.
The wife of Mr. Zhang of Ministry of Justice
came here to personally report
that her husband keeps 12 mistresses.
I heard more than half of the 12 mistresses
are from Wanxiang Pavilion.
Liu Ru Yan sent them to Mr. Zhang.
They only care about money, not the person,
and get along like real sisters.
As long as they get enough money,
they won't be jealous at all.
And Chen Jing Yi, the compiler in Hanlin.
She is well-read and gentle.
She is praised by the old ministers.
How could she be involved in such scandals?
I am nearly 70.
How could I do such a filthy thing?
This is a smear!
Don't be afraid.
If you don't speak out bravely,
you won't have a chance again.
Don't be afraid. Speak out bravely.
It was you
who used your position to harass me.
You also threatened my career
to keep me silent.
Otherwise, I'll have no place in the capital.
I believe some of the female officials
were also once persecuted by Mr. Jiang.
Do you dare to stand up with me?
If everyone remains silent,
these hypocrites will go unpunished.
In the future, more women will suffer.
As female officials,
we already face many difficulties.
We must stop this kind of misconduct.
It was you
who used your position to harass me.
Yes, it was you.
You also harassed me.
It was you who harassed me.
Take him away.
Why are you arresting me?
- Go.
- Why are you arresting me?
We also discovered
the Ministry of Personnel sold positions.
But for now,
some minor officials are behind it.
High officials are not involved yet.
All of you are involved
in selling official positions.
You're to be suspended and investigated.
Take them away.
What's going on?
Go.
- Go.
- Why are you arresting me?
Move!
Right now,
we've only caught a few small fish,
but the giant one behind Ling Yun Fei
is still lurking underwater.
We must stir up the water.
It's easy to catch the fish
from the muddy water.
On behalf of all ministers,
I impeach Meng Ting Hui of the Censorate
for exceeding her authority
and invading the privacy of high officials.
It's caused complaints throughout the court
and made everyone uneasy.
It's rare to see you all so united.
I am very pleased.
Since the Censorate acts so arrogantly,
you can directly report their negligence
and expose their illegal acts.
I will show them no mercy.
Do you have anything else to report?
Don't go yet, everyone.
The tea in the Censorate is getting cold.
Please come with me.
We haven't broken any law.
How can you detain us arbitrarily?
- That's right.
- Yes, why are you arresting us?
Because you fabricated charges
and maliciously impeached the Censorate.
I can detain you for 24 hours
on the charge of false accusation.
- Take them away.
- Yes.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, we're innocent!
Meng Ting Hui just lied!
- She is framing loyal officials!
- Your Majesty!
Move!
[Censorate]
Meng Ting Hui.
What gives you the right to detain us here?
- Right.
- Yes, why?
Why are you detaining us here?
You evil woman.
Unless you kill me,
I will submit memorials every day
to impeach you, you evil woman.
- Yes, that's right.
- Yes.
You are the bane of this country,
you evil woman.
Yes, you're the bane of this country.
You're the bane.
You evil woman, get out of the court.
I disdain to work with you.
I just invited all of you over
to have a cup of tea here.
Why are you so agitated?
We will not drink tea
from a bad official like you.
- That's right.
- Yes.
We will not drink your tea.
You evil woman, get out of the court.
- Get out.
- During last year's exam,
Academician Lin took bribes from candidates
and altered 13 exam papers.
Three of the candidates were illiterate,
while those who studied hard failed.
Someone vomited blood
and fainted on the spot.
Send him to the Supreme Court
and punish him by law.
Meng Ting Hui, this is personal revenge.
Yin Qing.
- I want to see His Majesty.
- Director Meng.
- Meng Ting Hui!
- There was heavy rain earlier this year.
Pan Wen Hai, the Minister of Works,
under the pretext of repairing the dam,
embezzled nearly 100,000 taels
of disaster relief funds,
destroying six villages downstream,
with countless casualties,
yet only three days after the disaster,
he bought 1,000 mu of fertile land.
1,000 mu?
Utter nonsense! That's a lie!
This is the evidence of his embezzlement.
- You--
- How dare you embezzle the relief funds!
Send him and the evidence
to the Ministry of Justice.
Remember to remind the Minister of Justice
that this is a felony crime
according to the Laws of Ning Empire.
I'm innocent!
Nonsense!
Utter nonsense!
Mr. Pan!
Next.
Meng Ting Hui!
You're doing this for private gain.
It's to get rid of dissidents.
His Majesty is out of his mind.
He actually favors only you.
Hear, hear!
- You evil woman!
- Why?
Shut up!
How dare you
speak recklessly of His Majesty's decisions?
Lord Gu, it's an honor to have you here.
Sorry for not greeting you properly.
They say the tea here tastes terrible,
but I want to try it.
Director Meng.
Would you offer me a cup of tea?
Your tea, please.
[Salary Records]
The Censorate has been fighting corruption.
As the head of all officials,
praised as a virtuous chancellor,
I should set an example
for the court officials
and actively cooperate
with the investigation.
Lord Gu,
I heard that Pan Wen Hai
and Academician Lin were both your students.
Director Meng, mind your words.
We are all court officials.
We serve His Majesty
and are only loyal to His Majesty.
If close associates of mine violate the law,
I will show them no mercy.
You're quite sensible, Lord Gu.
Speaking of close associates,
do you have any relatives?
I come from a humble family.
I'm the only son in my family,
placed with high hopes.
Director Meng,
you can investigate me as you wish.
Please enforce the law impartially
and act based on the truth.
I am willing to take this chance
to prove my integrity.
Lord Gu, are you really not worried
we might find something?
I act properly.
I'm not afraid of your investigation.
Here are my salary records for these years.
You may look at them.
Since you're so frank,
you must be innocent.
We naturally do not need
to spend too much time on you.
In the past, you helped me in my career.
I deeply believe
you're upright and honest.
Please.
Who says the tea here is not good?
I find it quite delicious.
All of you, please calm down.
Let's taste this tea together.
As colleagues,
we should fully cooperate with Director Meng.
Yes.
Meng Ting Hui is out of her mind.
She has thrown the six ministries into chaos.
Pan Wen Hai and Academician Lin
are already restless.
If the investigation continues like this--
Since Meng Ting Hui wants
to fight corruption,
I naturally have to cooperate.
Perhaps
we should leak out something.
Lord Gu, they are loyal to you.
Since they've set their fishing net,
we have to release some small fish.
Mr. Pan loves to buy land and houses,
doesn't he?
Have someone leak this to Meng Ting Hui.
As for how much she can dig up,
that depends on her ability.
Lord Gu, thank you for your full support
for our work.
Well, I will take my leave.
If you encounter any difficulties,
please have someone inform me.
Director Meng, I will see my teacher off.
Director, he clearly came prepared.
How should we respond?
The more he acts like this,
the more guilty he is.
Since he wants to put on this show,
we might as well play along.
Go and compile all the files related to him.
This old fox wants to use me
to show his honesty and integrity.
I want to see
whether he is truly honest
or hypocritical, with blood on his hands.
Blood moon in the sky!
The Black Bird returns!
A secret letter from Mr. Shangguan.
Although we failed to take Ying Gua's life,
the princess has gained trust
and got promoted.
Heaven bless Zhongwan!
May we restore our land!
Ying Gua rejected a marriage alliance
with Beijian.
Our Xuanyu Guards have snatched
30,000 dan of grain from the Ning Empire.
It is a heaven-sent opportunity.
In three days,
I'll go to Beijian to forge an alliance.
By our sharp sword,
the Ning Empire will change hands.
Heaven bless Zhongwan!
May we restore our land!
[Censorate]
[Beijian wants a marriage alliance,
but I don't want it. What I want is only you]
Yao, come and catch me!
Come on!
Yao, come on.
Shangguan.
Where are you?
Le Yan.
Master, I've finished.
Excellent brushwork,
but...
It lacks a finishing touch.
[Belated Spring]
Belated Spring.
At night, news of spring arrived.
It got me in the mood.
I secretly expressed my longing for love.
Only spring knew about my love.
This is Belated Spring.
Since Ling Yi passed away,
I've been feeling uneasy.
The winter is long,
and spring is far out of reach.
But that day,
when I put down the dagger in front of you,
I suddenly realized
the dead are gone,
but the living should live for themselves.
Le Yan, you made me live again.
In the future,
I want to live for myself once more.
It's wonderful that you think this way.
The other day, you were deeply sorrowful,
yet you still managed to assist Director Meng
in fighting corruption.
I admire you deeply,
and I also worry about you.
So I painted this spring scene for you.
Le Yan, all of this is because of you.
Only by your side can I be my true self.
A romantic relationship is forbidden
between teachers and students.
It's going to be a tough road.
But if I persevere,
Le Yan,
will you be brave for me, just this once?